University of Houston World War II Era Clippings
University of Houston Libraries
University of Houston World War II Era Clippings
1939-1944
Special Collections, University of Houston Libraries
University of Houston
3.50 Linear Feet
University of Houston W.W. II Clippings contains newspaper articles that mostly relate to the University of Houston during the years 1939-1944.
1996-008
Scope and Contents
University of Houston W.W. II Clippings contains newspaper articles that mostly relate to the University of Houston during the years 1939-1944. Some of the topics covered in these articles include the separation of the university from the Houston school system, Frontier Fiesta, and the university's contributions to the war effort through the offering of special war-related subject in areas including classes in navigation, diesel engine repair, map interpretation, aircraft engine repair, first-aid, and radio service.
The collection is separated by month with the folders placed in ascending order. Four folders containing undated material may be found at the end of the collection.
Forms part of the University Archives.
Index Terms
This Collection is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Corporate Name:
Frontier Fiesta; University of Houston
Genre/Form of Material:
Clippings
Topical Term:
World War, 1939-1945
Access Restrictions
Open for research.
Acquisition
Detailed Description
- Newspaper Articles
  The collection is separated by month with the folders placed in ascending order. Four folders containing undated material may be found at the end of the collection.
  - 1939 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - May, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - June, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - July, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - August, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - September, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - October, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - November, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - December, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - January,1941 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - February, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - March, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - April, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - May 1-15, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - May 16-30, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - June, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - July, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - August 1-15, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - August 16-31, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - September 1-15, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - September 16-30, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - October 1-15, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - October 16-31, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - November 1-15, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - November 16-30, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - December 1-15, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - December 16-30, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Frontier Fiesta, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Texas State Teachers Association (TSTA), 1941 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - January 1-15, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - January 16-31, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - February 1-15, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - February 16-29, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - March 1-15, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - March 16-31, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - April 1-15, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - April 16-30, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - May 1-15, 1942 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - May 16-31, 1942 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - June 1-15, 1942 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - June 16-30, 1942 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - July, 1942 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - August 1-15, 1942 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - August 16-31, 1942 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - September 1-15, 1942 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - September 16-30, 1942 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - October, 1942 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - November, 1942 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - December, 1942 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - January, 1943 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - February, 1943 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - March, 1943 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - April, 1943 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - May, 1943 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - June, 1943 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - July, 1943 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - August, 1943 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - September, 1943 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - October, 1943 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - November, 1943 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - December, 1943 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - January, 1944 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - February, 1944 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - March, 1944 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - April, 1944 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - May, 1944 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - June, 1944 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - July, 1944 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - August, 1944 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - September, 1944 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - October, 1944 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - November, 1944 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - December, 1944 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Undated 1 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Undated 2 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Undated 3 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Undated 4 (Box 4, Folder 16)